<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on My Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on My Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Cai</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 22:31:49 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Feb 25 - Thoughts Are the Second Derivative of Reality</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202502monthly/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Feb 2025 22:31:49 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202502monthly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;good-winds-good-fortune&#34;&gt;Good Winds, Good Fortune&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I randomly clicked on my Bilibili favorites and saw a bunch of videos I saved years ago.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The very first one I favorited was &lt;em&gt;Learn to Build a Gundam Model in 13 Minutes&lt;/em&gt;—haha.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The forgotten memories of the internet came rushing back to me.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;hr&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Many creators&amp;rsquo; last updates were in 2024.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some have deleted their accounts, yet their videos remain watchable.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Some transitioned from food vlogging to e-commerce, from study content to the automotive sector.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Jan 25 - New Semester &amp; The Plan to Become an MLE</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202501monthly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2025 23:52:31 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202501monthly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;starting-school&#34;&gt;Starting School&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The spring semester feels much more relaxed compared to when I first arrived in the United States during the fall. Attending classes, listening to lectures, doing homework, and taking exams have all become routine.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;However, course registration remains as competitive as ever—there are always more students than available classes, and the waitlists for popular courses are incredibly tight. For example, I ended up on the waitlist for a graduate course; on top of that, I’m taking 8803 Hardware Software Codesign, 6133 Physical Design Automation, Computer Architecture, and a VIP course on Responsible AI.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024 yearly - Evacuation From 2024</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/2024yearly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 17:08:55 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/2024yearly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;2024: A Pivotal Year&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Graduating from undergrad and leaving the familiar campus that shaped the past four years.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A 15-hour flight from China to Atlanta.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;My first time leaving the country, my first time in the U.S., and my first time visiting Latin America.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h2 id=&#34;xbotpark&#34;&gt;XbotPark&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;At the beginning of the year, I spent time at the XbotPark base in Dongguan, meeting a group of entrepreneurial peers and participating in some “I to E” (innovator to entrepreneur) activities.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Dec 24 - Long December and Solo Trip to Latino American</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202412monthly/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Dec 2024 16:59:58 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202412monthly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;winter-holiday&#34;&gt;Winter Holiday&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;A month-long winter break, spent lounging in the apartment. Before I knew it, my sleep schedule had shifted to match China’s time zone—falling asleep at 5 a.m. and waking up at 4 p.m.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;I had long planned to take a trip during the winter holiday.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;Central America is a major coffee-producing region. Bogota, often mentioned by my friend Eel Brother, naturally became the first destination of my trip to Colombia.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nov 24 - Cooking adventures and end of semester</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202411monthly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 20:31:04 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202411monthly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;third-month&#34;&gt;Third Month&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November marks my third month in the US. Time flies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It feels like I haven&amp;rsquo;t accomplished much - still stumbling with spoken English, and job hunting hasn&amp;rsquo;t even made it to my agenda yet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month I experimented with many Southern Chinese dishes: steamed beef shank, three-cup chicken, roasted potatoes, spicy grilled fish, steamed sea bass, and grilled lamb chops. Hope I can maintain this enthusiasm for cooking next month too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Oct 24 - After the US election</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202410monthly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 22:14:38 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202410monthly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;global-contraction-and-trumps-victory&#34;&gt;Global Contraction and Trump&amp;rsquo;s Victory&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The global right-wing shift has been around so long we almost forgot about it. Recently, Swiss universities added more restrictions on Chinese student admissions, Florida limited Chinese student enrollment, ETH Zurich implemented measures restricting Chinese PhD candidates, and rumors suggest EPFL will also stop considering Chinese applicants. Add to this the US 10043 policy and visa restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The US and its allies are setting up increasingly more barriers for Chinese students, creating a trend where those who&amp;rsquo;ve left might not easily return, and those who haven&amp;rsquo;t left might not get the chance. Chinese students, besides choosing alternative countries, are powerless in this situation. We can expect increased difficulty in securing spots in Hong Kong and Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
