<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Monthly on My Blog</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/en/tags/monthly/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Monthly on My Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Cai</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 20:31:04 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/en/tags/monthly/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>November monthly - Cooking adventures and end of semester</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202411monthly/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Dec 2024 20:31:04 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202411monthly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;third-month&#34;&gt;Third Month&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;November marks my third month in the US. Time flies.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It feels like I haven&amp;rsquo;t accomplished much - still stumbling with spoken English, and job hunting hasn&amp;rsquo;t even made it to my agenda yet.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;This month I experimented with many Southern Chinese dishes: steamed beef shank, three-cup chicken, roasted potatoes, spicy grilled fish, steamed sea bass, and grilled lamb chops. Hope I can maintain this enthusiasm for cooking next month too.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>October monthly - After the US election</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202410monthly/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 30 Oct 2024 22:14:38 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/en/posts/202410monthly/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;global-contraction-and-trumps-victory&#34;&gt;Global Contraction and Trump&amp;rsquo;s Victory&lt;/h2&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The global right-wing shift has been around so long we almost forgot about it. Recently, Swiss universities added more restrictions on Chinese student admissions, Florida limited Chinese student enrollment, ETH Zurich implemented measures restricting Chinese PhD candidates, and rumors suggest EPFL will also stop considering Chinese applicants. Add to this the US 10043 policy and visa restrictions.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;The US and its allies are setting up increasingly more barriers for Chinese students, creating a trend where those who&amp;rsquo;ve left might not easily return, and those who haven&amp;rsquo;t left might not get the chance. Chinese students, besides choosing alternative countries, are powerless in this situation. We can expect increased difficulty in securing spots in Hong Kong and Singapore.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
